SUSHAN THAPA

Sudbury, Ontario, Canada · +1 249 979 4278 sushan.thapa1010@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ersushanthapa

A software developer with two years of experience overseeing the development of software applications from conception to launch. Highly motivated and enthusiastic developer seeking a position in IT industries.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCER, REMOTASKS | JAN 2024 - PRESENT

- Solve coding problems, writing functional and efficient code to meet the requirements
- Evaluate the quality of AI generated code, including human-readable summaries of coding rationale.
- Writing human-readable summaries of coding problems and solutions.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, JAVRA SOFTWARE | MARCH 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

- Successfully migrated a critical application from .NET framework to the latest .NET core, ensuring improved performance, scalability, and compatibility with modern technologies.
- Developed Windows service application that runs in the background job which converted the XML data from the source to CSV format and synced it to salesforce platform using Bulk Api 2.0
- Implemented continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines in Azure devops, automating the deployment process for MVC applications both in the azure cloud and on-premises environments.
- Developed a cross-platform mobile application using Microsoft's .NET MAUI, delivering a seamless user experience across multiple devices.
- Designed and implemented web APIs using .NET, providing efficient communication and data exchange between various components of the software ecosystem.
- Conducted performance tuning in SQL server databases, optimizing queries and database structures to enhance overall application responsiveness.

TRAINEE, JAVRA SOFTWARE | MARCH 2022 - MAY 2022

- Developed Student Result Management System with ASP .NET CORE MVC using C# language.
- Employed agile development methodologies to enhance project flexibility and responsiveness to changing requirements.
- SQL Server database design And Implementation.

EDUCATION

PG in MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT, CAMBRIAN COLLEGE, SUDBURY, ONTARIO, CANADA

B.E IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, KATHMANDU ENGINEERING COLLEGE, KATHMANDU, NEPAL

<u>SKILLS</u> <u>CERTIFICATIONS</u>

Salesforce
C#, .NET, Microsoft Azure
OPython
Azure Fundamentals
Azure Al Fundamentals

SQL SERVER

AngularHTML/CSS/JS